SHIBA DEB

{ Portfolio: website, Github: shiba517, LinkedIn: shiba-deb-2099b6105/, Email: shiba.cdeb@gmail.com, Phone: 07960545799, Location: London, UK }

Junior Full Stack Developer

I am a recently graduated Junior Fullstack Developer knocking on the doors of the tech world to start a new chapter in my life. Comfortable in my skills of SQL, JavaScript, Python, Django, MongoDB, AWS, and HTML & CSS. I also bring experience in communications with the public which came in use whilst working in the hospitality industry, and have been exposed to the world of creativity with my time in hair and beauty. Creative, collaborative, and certainly open to challenges.

Techinical Skills

Languages

- JavaScript
- Python
- HTML5
- CSS3
- SQL

Databases

- MongoDB
- AWS
- PySpark
- Pig
- MySQL

- JQuery
- Django
- React
- Bootstrap
- Materialize
- Hadoop
- Boto3
- Streamlit
- **Pandas**

Frameworks/Libraries Version control

• Github

Education and Training

Code Institute (2021 - 2022) Full Stack Developer - Merit

Westminster University (2016 - 2018)

Nutrition

London Metropolitan University (2009 - 2012)

Business and Marketing (2:1)

SAKS Academy Hairdressing (2015 - 2016)

Achieved whilst at Windle & Moodie Hairdressers

Professional Experience

Sparta Global (2022)

Junior Data Engineer

Trained to a proficient level of knowledge and skills with SQL and NoSQL databases. Used Boto3 on selected IDE to make use of AWS services. Implemented ETL/ELT, Hadoop and Pig skills with AWS EMR services. Projects also tested skills with utilising OOP model alongside Pandas and AWS S3 service.

PGL Adventure Centre (2021 - present)

Catering assistant

Being part of a team to prepare a canteen and then serve to feed hundreds of childrens three times a day. High volume and tight timings were the main challenges which pushed me to

- Prioritise and be efficient with tasks
- Approach situations in a calmly manner

The May Fair Hotel (2016 - 2020)

Events team-leader

It was my responsibility to help the events manager to set up and run the event smoothly. Due to the hotel being the company's (Radisson Blu) flagship hotel, we had to be on top of our game on how we deliver the service and experience the company demands. A big part of that happening was following guidelines, personal intuition/initiative and organisation. I learnt a lot on how to

- Communicate effectively with different departments
- Encourage groups of people to work together
- Deal with demanding difficult guests without negatively affecting their experience

Windle and Moodie Hairdressers (2015 - 2016)

Trainee hairdresser

Assist high demanding senior hairdressers with their work on their clients whilst also learning from them all in a fast-paced environment. Whilst working here, I was exposed to

- Constant new techniques and ideas
- Create a custom experience with clients
- Implement my learnings into practise

Transferable Skills

- **Time management** and **Organisation** Working in hospitality and hair had me exercise my use of energy and time to complete tasks in order for other tasks to happen
- Leadership and Empathy I have lead many teams to perform in tough circumstances ranging from outside of work conditions such as morale, lack of experience and difficult work attitude
- Collaborative and Problem-solving My independence had taught me to approach tasks in a
 positive, structured manner whilst also knowing the importance of learning and listening
 from others to achieve a task

Interests and Hobbies

- Hiking Not a stranger to various hiking groups
- Cycling Saved many train fares by cycling to other towns/cities
- Travelling Visited many small towns and cities around Europe